Guide to the Jewish oral history project audio recordings 1972-1977
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Jewish oral history project audio recordings
1972-1982
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0324
American West Center
141 audiocassetes and 37 compact discs. Each CD has a duplicate copy.
The Jewish oral history project audio recordings (1972-1982) document the experiences of various people of the Jewish community in Utah and surrounding areas. The American West Center conducted this and other ethnic oral history projects in an attempt to record the experiences Utah's eithnic minorities.
Organizational History
In 1964, History professors A. R. Mortensen and Gregory Crampton conceived the University of Utah's American West Center (originally called the Western History Center) as an institution devoted exclusively to research on the American West. As a part of its mission to create and disseminate knowledge about the American West, the center established the ongoing Ethnic Oral Histories Project to explore the experiences of Utah members of Native American and ethnic immigrant communities, including the Jewish community.
The Jewish oral history project audio recordings (1972-1982) document the experiences of various people of the Jewish community in Utah and surrounding areas.
The materials are arranged by format:
Audiocassettes are arranged alphabetically by the interviewee's last name; recordings of subjects who were interviewed more than once are not necessarily listed in chronological order.
Compact discs are arranged chronologically by interview date.
Some subjects are represented by interviews held on both cassette and CD.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
Transcripts can be found in the Jewish oral history project (Accn 1629) and Interviews with Jews in Utah (Accn 998) in the Manuscripts Division of Special Collections.
Utah--Emigration and immigration; Utah--Ethnic relations; Jews, American--Utah--Interviews; Immigrants--Utah--Interviews; Children of immigrants--Utah--Interviews; Jews--Utah--Cultural assimilation; Judaism; Sound Recordings; Oral Histories; Sound recordings
- Sadie Appleman, 1982 May 19; Audiocassette (Cassette 1)
- Michael Arnovitz, 1982 November 30; 1982 December 06; 1982 December 12; Audiocassette (Cassette 2-5)
- Rose Arnovitz, 1983 April 14; 1983 March 16; Audiocassette (Cassette 6-9)
- Bernice Bernstein, 1982 June 17; Audiocassette (Cassette 10)
- Herman Bernstein, 1982 June 16; Audiocassette (Cassette 11)
- Sam Bernstein, 1982 July 01; Audiocassette (Cassette 12)
- Abe Cline, 1983 May 19; 1982 June 02; 1982 June 06; 1983 June 15; 1982 June 20; Audiocassette (Cassette 13-19)
- Jeannie Dupler, 1982 June 18; Audiocassette (Cassette 20)
- Harold Findling, 1982 June 25; Audiocassette (Cassette 21-22)
- Simon Frank, 1982 June 28-29; Audiocassette (Cassette 23-24)
- Alberta Freshman, 1982 June 03; 1982 June 07; Audiocassette (Cassette 25-26)
- Doris N. Guss, 1982 July 09; Audiocassette (Cassette 27)
- Samuel Guss, 1982 January 20; Audiocassette (Cassette 28-29)
- Eugene Hertz, 1982 November 24; Audiocassette (Cassette 30-31)
- Esther Klein, 1982 November 17; 1982 December 15; Audiocassette (Cassette 32-33)
- Esther Landa, 1982 May 11; 1982 May 16; Audiocassette (Cassette 34-36)
- Betsy Bamberger Lesser, 1983 January 27; 1983 May 26; 1983 May 28; Audiocassette (Cassette 37-39)
- Fred Livden, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 40)
- JoAnne McGillis, 1982 May 13; 1982 June 02; Audiocassette (Cassette 41-42)
- Howard Marcus, 1982 May 24; 1982 June 07; Audiocassette (Cassette 43-44)
- Sidney Matz, 1985 November 12; 1985 November 19; 1985 November 25; Audiocassette (Cassette 45-48)
- Harry Miller, 1982 June 17; 1986 February 27; 1986 October 28; Audiocassette (Cassette 49-51)
- Norman Nathan, 1983 February 17; 1983 February 24; 1983 May 12; 1983 May 19; Audiocassette (Cassette 52-55)
- Rose Nord, 1983 April 21; 1983 April 28; Audiocassette (Cassette 56-57)
- Milton Pepper, 1982 June 29; 1982 July 23; Audiocassette (Cassette 58-59)
- Sonia Pepper; Rose Arnovitz, 1983 January 13-14; Audiocassette (Cassette 60-61)
- Bernie Rose, 1983 January 17; 1983 January 20; 1983 January 25; Audiocassette (Cassette 62-65)
- Isaac Rose, 1982 June 16; 1982 July 02; 1982 July 23; Audiocassette (Cassette 66-68)
- Joseph Rosenblatt, 1982 June 04; 1982 May 21; 1982 June 11; 1982 July 02; 1982 July 10; 1982 July 17; 1982 July 25; 1982 July 31; 1982 August 07; Audiocassette (Cassette 69-77)
- Sophie Rosenthal, 1983 January 19; Audiocassette (Cassette 78)
- Helen Saudack, 1982 June 03; Audiocassette (Cassette 79-80)
- A. Wally Saudack, 1982 June 22; 1982 June 29; Audiocassette (Cassette 81-83)
- Joel Shapiro, 1982 May 26; 1982 June 09; 1982 June 15; 1982 June 20; 1982 August 11; Audiocassette (Cassette 84-89)
- Cecelia Siegal, 1982 May 17; Audiocassette (Cassette 90)
- Dal Siegal, 1982 May 10; 1982 May 15; 1982 May 18; Audiocassette (Cassette 91-94)
- Harry Smith, 1982 June 02; Audiocassette (Cassette 95-96)
- Marjoroe Smith, 1982 June 09; Audiocassette (Cassette 97)
- Corinne Sweet, 1982 July 08; 1982 November 16; 1982 November 22; 1982 December 09; Audiocassette (Cassette 98-101)
- Ralph Tanenbaum, 1983 January 24; 1983 June 18; Audiocassette (Cassette 102-105)
- Sade Tanenbaum, 1982 June 06; 1983 July 24; Audiocassette (Cassette 106-107)
- Harry Doctorman, 1986 March 06; 1986 March 13; Audiocassette (Cassette 108)
- Joe Doctoman and son Harry, 1986 February 24; Audiocassette (Cassette 110)
- David Freedman, 1984 June 18; Audiocassette (Cassette 111)
- Jack Goodman, 1987 November 16; Audiocassette (Cassette 112-113)
- Abe Guss, 1987 December 01; Audiocassette (Cassette 114)
- Victor Kassel, 1987 September 17; 1987 September 25; 1987 October 08; Audiocassette (Cassette 115-117)
- Laurence D. Loeb, 1987 September 15; 1987 October 20; Audiocassette (Cassette 118-119)
- Jerry Lutzker, 1987 December 24; Audiocassette (Cassette 120)
- Harry Miller, 1982 June 17; 1986 October 28; Audiocassette (Cassette 121-122)
- Isaac Rose, 1987 April 28-29; Audiocassette (Cassette 123-124)
- Milton A. Rosen, 1982 June 10; Audiocassette (Cassette 125-126)
- Joseph Rosenblatt, 1983 October 21; 1984 October 03; Audiocassette (Cassette 127-128)
- Eva Seigal, 1984 July 12; Audiocassette (Cassette 129)
- Rabbi Eric Silver, 1986 February 13; 1986 February 26; 1986 March 10; 1986 April 03; Audiocassette (Cassette 130-133)
- Abe Wagner, 1983 December 21; 1983 February 28; Audiocassette (Cassette 134-136)
- Izzy Wagner, 1983 August 09; 1983 August 15; 1983 August 26; 1983 September 08; Audiocassette (Cassette 137-140)
- Max Wilson; Anatole Zucker, 1982 August 13; Audiocassette (Cassette 141)
- Clair Steris Vonstien, 1972 August 01; H-3-01; Compact disc (Disc 142)
  Mrs. Vonstien discusses the history of Jews in Utah and the Intermountain West.
- Ben Arnovitz, 1972 August 11; H-4-01; Compact disc (Disc 143-144)
  Mr. Arnovitz discusses the history of his family, work, and his religion.
- Ben Arnovitz; unidentified Native American, 1972 August 11; H-4-02; Compact disc (Disc 145)
  Mr. Arnovitz continues his discussion regarding Judaism in Salt Lake City. The end of track 3 through track 10 contains an interview with an unidentified Native American discussing World War II.
- Ed Isen, 1972 August 17; H-5-01&02; Compact disc (Disc 146-147)
- Max Callwin, 1972 August 18; H-6-01&02; Compact disc (Disc 148-149)
- Eva Seigal, 1972 August 22; H-7-01&02; Compact disc (Disc 150-151)
- Sarah Paulmrands, 1972 August 24; H-8-01&02; Compact disc (Disc 152-153)
- Phillip Pearlman, 1972 September 01; H-9-01&02; Compact disc (Disc 154-155)
- Ray Bernstien, 1972 September 14; H-12-01; Compact disc (Disc 156)
- Maurice Warshaw, 1972 October 28; 1972 November 07; 1972 November 14; 1973 February 06; H-13a-01&02, H13b-01, H14-01, H-19-01; Compact disc (Disc 157-160, 162)
- Ester Landa, 1972 December 26; H-16-01; Compact disc (Disc 161)
- Charles Poritzky, 1973 June 18; 1973 July 01; H-25-01&02, H-26-01&02; Compact disc (Disc 163-166)
- Min Crutcher, 1973 July 25; H-27-01&02 H-28-01&02; Compact disc (Disc 167-170)
- Maurice Hayden, 1973 November 08; H-29-01&02; Compact disc (Disc 171-172)
  Shaare Zedek Congregation.
- Sam and Abe Bernstein, 1973 November 04; H-29a-01; Compact disc (Disc 173)
- Harry Olchule, 1976 April 29; H-31-01&02; Compact disc (Disc 174-175)
- Unidentified interview, undated; H-33-01; Compact disc (Disc 176)
- J. Pulman Waters, Samuel Newhouse, 1977 July 16; H-34-01; Compact disc (Disc 177)
- Doris Dearis, 1982 June; H-36-01&02, H-37-01&02; Compact disc (Disc 178-179)